<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Marcello Galhardo</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Marcello Galhardo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 09:02:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcellogalhardo.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep Models</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/10/07/deep-models/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 09:02:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/10/07/deep-models/</guid><description>Modeling is a critical task in Software Development: good models reduce the risk of bugs, increase readability and improve maintainability. However, we can often see developers focusing on &amp;ldquo;How can I code this?&amp;quot;, and they are done with their task when they find a way to code it. This inherently reduces the domain modeling to the abuse of primitives and shallow design where any inconsistent state is allowed.
To better explain, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the hypothetical requirements:</description></item><item><title>Using Compose Beta on AS 4.1</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/03/30/using-compose-beta-on-as-4-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:37:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/03/30/using-compose-beta-on-as-4-1/</guid><description>Jetpack Compose hit Beta! Many teams are excited to experiment with Compose, but as you might know, since 1.0.0-alpha04, the compiler has been refactored to a new group and became incompatible with the current Android Studio (AS) 4.1 stable:
Compose Version 1.0.0-alpha04 is only compatible with Android Studio 4.2 Canary 13 and later.
Been forced to use a Canary version of AS is a real bummer. There are cases in which you want to explore Compose in a real-world application (e.</description></item><item><title>N26 Path to Anvil</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/02/05/n26-path-to-anvil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 09:02:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/02/05/n26-path-to-anvil/</guid><description>This post represents my personal experience while working at N26. I do not speak for the company nor by other employees.
N26 Android App current codebase has a million lines of code, 280+ modules, and 30+ engineers working in 4 different countries and different timezones in a mono repository. Our modules are divided into features and libraries, and we have been using &amp;ldquo;Sample Apps&amp;rdquo; for years now as our full app build time might take up to 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Humble Views, Proud ViewModels</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/02/01/humble-views-proud-viewmodels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 09:02:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2021/02/01/humble-views-proud-viewmodels/</guid><description>The Android Community has long advocated that Activities and Fragments were views - but this perception has changed over time. For good. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deep into how to design views and view models, how they wire to a LifecycleOwner, and how this can positively impact your&amp;rsquo;s app testability.
To better describe how to build humble views we will be developing an elementary Sign-Up form with an email, a password text field and two buttons: a cancel that pops the user&amp;rsquo;s back stack and a sign up that creates an account and moves the user to the home screen.</description></item><item><title>Naming Factory Methods</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2020/02/01/naming-factory-methods/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:02:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/posts/2020/02/01/naming-factory-methods/</guid><description>When talking about Factory Methods, extension functions tend to be favored in Kotlin - but it might be a challenge to name these functions in a discoverable way without polluting your project&amp;rsquo;s namespace. A good source of inspiration is Kotlin&amp;rsquo;s Standard library: it contains many examples we can use as a base when deciding how to design a function.
Wrapping an instance If you intend to get a given instance and adapt to one different object to follow another contract, for example, creating a ViewModelProvider.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/about/</guid><description>Software engineer with over 6 years of experience with Android. I have been building software professionally since 2012, starting on Web and Backend, later on Desktop, and finally, on Android. I worked with small teams at Quandoo, to dozens of engineers working on the same codebase at N26 and Delivery Hero. At N26, I worked on the Consumer App and later led the Android Platform Team. The apps I worked on had millions of downloads used in more than 20 countries.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/talks/</guid><description> April 29, 2021: Anvil na Prática (PT-BR) June 05, 2019: Railway Oriented Programming with Kotlin April 17, 2019: Effective Kotlin March 01, 2019: Modularizing Legacy Apps November 11, 2018: Android Modular Architecture January 24, 2017: Introduction to Dagger 2 January 24, 2017: Introdução ao Dagger 2 (PT-BR) September 06, 2016: SOLID no Android 2 (PT-BR)</description></item><item><title>Uses</title><link>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/uses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcellogalhardo.dev/uses/</guid><description>Software File Manager: Marta Window Manager: Tiles Window Switcher: Contexts Menu Bar Manager: Dozer Menu Bar Calendar: Itsycal Diagrams, Quick: Diagrams Diagrams, Work: PlantUML IDE: IntelliJ IDEA with Dracula Pro Knowledge Management: Obsidian with Zettelkasten Terminal: Warp Screen Sharing, Pair Programming: CoScreen Hardware Professional Machine: 2020 13&amp;quot; Macbook Pro Mechanical Keyboard: Keychron K2 Wireless Mechanical Keyboard Apple Magic Mouse Ergonomics Chair: JÄRVFJÄLLET</description></item></channel></rss>